Contact

grlthinker@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/melissahunter-dnp-rn-ccrn-8aa02186 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills MSN, RN, CCRN ACLS, PALS Critical Care

Certifications CCRN

Honors-Awards

STOP Snoring with a Bang!: Perioperative screening of patients for risk factors associated with obstructive sleep apnea.

Melissa Hunter, DNP, RN, CCRN

Johns Hopkins University School of Nursing Rising Sun, Maryland

Summary

Experienced Education Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Nursing Education, Medical-Surgical, Medication Administration, Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS), and Intensive Care. Strong operations professional with a Post Masters Certificate focused in Nursing Education from Johns Hopkins School of Nursing.

Experience

Johns Hopkins School of Nursing Fulltime Faculty January 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months) Baltimore, Maryland

Teaching JHUSON Masters Entry Nursing students in clinical setting with combine implementation of simulation to enhance learning and nursing skills. Courses: Foundations, Common, Chronic, Complex, and Senior Practicum Synthesis

UM Upper Chesapeake Health 6 years 2 months Education Specialist Evening Resource January 2019 - September 2019 (9 months) Havre De Grace, Maryland

PeriAnesthesia Education Specialist Pre-Surgical/Pre-op/PACU & Orthopedic/Neuro-Spine Unit August 2013 - January 2019 (5 years 6 months)

Bel air, Maryland

PeriAnesthesia Nurse Educator at University of Maryland Upper Chesapeake Medical Center and Harford Memorial Hospital. CCRN certification. New Team Member Orientation. MediTech Documentation. ACLS/PALS/CPR Instructor.

The Johns Hopkins University
Adjunct Faculty
August 2012 - January 2019 (6 years 6 months)

Teaching JHUSON nursing students in clinical setting with combine implementation of simulation to enhance learning and nursing skills.

Courses: Adult Health II and Patient Center Care

Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center Registered Nurse July 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 2 months)

PeriAnesthesia Care Unit. Charge Nurse Duties/ Preceptor/Practicum Nursing Students. Recovery of Surgical Patients from Anesthesia: critical care patients/ neuro/spinal/gastric bypass/ vascular/ embolization neuro & vascular/ burns/ GYN/ortho/ pediatric general surgery

Magnet Council Chair

St. Joseph Medical Center/ University of MD Registered Nurse May 2007 - July 2010 (3 years 3 months) Towson, MD

Critical Care Nurse/ Charge Nurse Duties/Preceptor. Caring for critical care patients status post cardiac thoracic/cardiac cath lab/ neuro-spinal surgeries/ vascular/ septic/ medical/ general surgery/ balloon pump/ continuos renal therapy

Nurses RX Registered Nurse June 2003 - May 2008 (5 years) Travel

Travel Nurse in Critical Care Area from Baltimore, MD, Philadelphia,PA, Phoenix, AZ and San Diego, Ca.

Areas include: cardiac thoracic/ trauma/ neurosurgery/ cardiac cath lab/ medical ICU/ surgical ICU/ neuro ICU

LifeBridge Health
Registered Nurse
August 1998 - May 2005 (6 years 10 months)
Baltimore, Maryland Area

Critical Care Nurse: ICU/ IMC charge nurse duties/ preceptor: cardiac thoracic/ trauma/neuro/ ortho/ general surgery/ medical/ sepsis/pulmonary

MedStar Health Union Memorial Hospital Registered Nurse July 1995 - September 1999 (4 years 3 months) Med-surg and Critical Care

Education

The Johns Hopkins University

Doctorate of Nurse Practice, Executive · (2015 - 2017)

Notre Dame of Maryland University

Master of Science (MS), Nursing Education · (2010 - 2012)

Notre Dame of Maryland University
Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing Science (2008 - 2010)

Notre Dame of Maryland University Bachelor of Arts (BA), Philosophy · (1997 - 2001)

Cecil College

Associate of Arts and Sciences (AAS), Nursing Science · (1993 - 1995)